osha.gov 2012-06-23

# U.S. Department of Labor -- Privacy and Security Statement

Thank you for visiting the Department of Labor (DOL or Department) website and reviewing our privacy and security statement. DOL is committed to maintaining the privacy of your personal information and the security of our computer systems. With respect to the collection, use and disclosure of personally identifiable information (PII), DOL makes every effort to ensure compliance with applicable federal law, including, but not limited to, The Privacy Act of 1974, The Paperwork Reduction Act of 1995, and The Freedom of Information Act.

As a general rule, the Department does not collect personally identifiable information when you visit our site unless you choose to provide such information. The information we collect varies based on what you do when visiting our site. 

_If you respond to an online request for personal information:_

The information requested by the Department will be used to respond to your inquiry or to provide you with the service associated with the request. When this information is requested, a customized "Privacy Notice" will describe fully the reasons for collecting it and will provide a description of the Department's intended use of the information. This Privacy Notice will appear in one of two places. It will either be on the webpage where the information is collected or it will be accessible through a link prominently displayed immediately preceding the information request.

_If you visit our site to read or download information, we collect and store the following information:_

  * The name of the domain from which you access the Internet (for example, dol.gov, if you are connecting from the Department of Labor's computer account).
  * The date and time you access our site.
  * The Internet address of the website from which you directly linked to our site.

This information is used by software programs on our website to collect summary statistics that allow us to assess the number of visitors to the different sections of our site, identify what information is of most and least interest, determine technical design specifications, monitor system performance, and help us make our site more useful to visitors.

_If you identify yourself by sending an e-mail containing personal information:_

You may send us personally identifiable information in an electronic mail message - for example you may send us your mailing address when requesting that information be mailed to you. This information is used solely for responding to your requests for information or records. We may forward your e-mail to other government employees who are better able to fulfill your requests. Should you wish to file a request under the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA), instructions are provided at http://www.dol.gov/dol/foia/.

_If you link to other sites outside DOL:_

Our website has many links to other sites. When you link to any of these sites, you are no longer on our site and are subject to the privacy policy of the new site.

_Social Media and Third Party Sites:_

In addition to the Department's official websites, the Department uses social media and third party sites to provide DOL content in a different format that may be useful or interesting to you. When we use these sites, the information we provide is consistent with the intended purpose of the DOL website. No PII may be requested from or collected by DOL on social media sites. The privacy protection provided on social media and third party sites that are not a part of DOL websites may not be the same as the privacy protection given by the DOL and described here.

_Cookie Use Notice:_

Cookies are small pieces of temporary data that are exchanged between a website and a user's computer which enable a "session," or "dialog," to be established between the two machines. The Department does not use cookies to collect any PII from users or to track user activities beyond our websites. The Department does not maintain copies of cookies on our websites after you leave our websites.

The Department employs "cookies" to provide better service to its customers. With the session established, the Department is able to tailor its responses (i.e., identify and provide you with the information you want) and help you traverse our webpages in the most efficient and effective manner possible. The session is often broken when the Department's server does not receive further requests from your computer or you simply exit your browser.

The Department limits its use of cookies to "session cookies" types of cookies that are temporarily stored in your computer's memory. Session cookies are normally deleted from a user's computer when the user logs off the computer or the user exits the browser. The Department does not issue "persistent cookies," which are cookies that could be stored permanently on your workstation and reused each time you visit the Department's website. Some social media and third party sites that display information from the Department may use persistent cookie technology. Most Internet browsers automatically accept persistent cookies. Although using persistent cookies may create a better experience for you, these sites should also work without them. If you don't want to accept cookies, you can edit your browser's options to stop accepting persistent cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the websites you visit.

* * *

For security purposes and to ensure that this service remains available to all users, our Web site also employs software programs to monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage. 

Unauthorized attempts to upload information or change information on this service are strictly prohibited and may be punishable under the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986 and The National Information Infrastructure Protection Act of 1996.
